# MONFERD COLLIN

Hollis, NY 11423 | (646) 912-3745 | monferd.j.collin@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/monferd-collin | github.com/mjc695

# TARGET ROLE: SOFTWARE ENGINEER

# **SUMMARY QUALIFICATIONS**

Motivated, success-oriented, and versatile professional with a proven track record of mobilizing wide-ranging computer programming and software engineering knowledge toward excellent work strategies and success-yielding projects. Infused with 4+ years of experience in web development and software engineering. Driven to employ the necessary broad-based skills in working both independently and with teams with an active goal of delivering short- and long-term superior results. Possess a high sense of responsibility, an impeccable work ethic, and a commendable record of dependability and integrity.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

Software Development | Agile Methodologies | Computer Programming | Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) | Web Development | Web Services | Web Applications | Requirements Analysis | Software Design | Software Project Management | Industrial Electronics | Adaptability | Attention to Detail | Critical Thinking & Problem Solving | Excellent Communication Skills | Strong Work Ethic

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Software Engineer | DISYS at Meta - New York, NY

May 2022 - May 2023

- Build front-end applications in React and Hack while facilitating active collaboration with product designers and researchers.
- ⇒ Ensure success in developing an adaptive audio player in Swift, which uses motion detection to adapt various song profiles.
- ➡ Maintain a commitment to the continuous improvement of patterns and ideas by conducting UXR with other Engineers.

#### **Freelance Developer**

Dec 2021 - May 2022

- Formulated and implemented a strategy informing and advertising natural living through the use of blogs and resale.
- ⇒ Performed website development through the use of Google Firebase, which allowed for easy traffic analysis and improvement.
- Took advantage of Firebase Hosting and Github's continuous integration mechanisms for successful website deployment.
- ⇒ Utilized JSX and AJAX for success and efficiency in the conversion of multiple website mockups into HTML and JavaScript.

#### Full Stack Web Developer | Dynable - New York, NY

Jan 2019 - Dec 2020

- → Produced an e-commerce website tailored for the sale of food items using React, Redux and Express while maintaining collaboration with a designer to ensure visual attractiveness and optimized website functionalities.
- Developed and integrated a filter that eliminated all online shop listings that contained users' allergens upon their input.
- Executed conversions of website mockups into HTML and JavaScript with their corresponding express APIs and SQL.

#### OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Substitute Paraprofessional | New York City Department of Education - New York, NY

Feb 2020 - Nov 2021

### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

Full Stack Development | Room8 (Video Presentation: https://bit.ly/2WDrwra)

November 2018 - December 2018

Built a web app employing data visualization and algorithms to allow users to source for potential roommates and obtain matching scores. Utilized d3 and React to create a map showing data locations.

#### Full Stack Development | Mimsy Medical

**November 2018** 

Developed an e-commerce website geared for medical supplies on Heroku. Built the front-end with React and Redux, while the back-end with Express and Sequelize. Obtained knowledge of the use of passport and stripe APIs to secure back-end routes and conduct transactions. Utilized Google oAuth for user login and product purchases.

## LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS

## Certification in Web Development | FullStack Academy of Code

2018

#### **EDUCATION**

# Fullstack Web Development | FullStack Academy of Code

2018

Bachelor of Science in Science and Technology Studies | New York University – Tandon School of Engineering

2016

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript | React | Redux | React Native | Typescript | Express | PostgreSQL | CSS | HTML | Node | Heroku | Google Firebase | Swift | Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook) | Google Suite | Adobe Suite | Social Media (Facebook, Instagram)